KEVIN FLANAGAN

Ballinasloe, Co. Galway | 083-3123122 | flanagank777@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Customer Support Engineer transitioning to a career in software development with a keen interest in data management having worked with Healthcare Data Management Systems with Siemens Healthineers.

Demonstrated proficiency in troubleshooting, diagnosing, and resolving issues across a range of mechanical, electrical, and computer-based systems. Excel in providing exceptional customer service by effectively communicating technical solutions and delivering comprehensive user training.

Currently pursuing a Diploma in Full Stack Software Development with three of the required five projects completed. My aptitude for learning new technologies and dedication to customer-centric solutions make me a valuable asset to any organization aiming to enhance operational efficiencies and deliver outstanding support services.

EDUCATION

2023 to Present Diploma: Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute, Dublin, Ireland.

Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland

Technical Syllabus

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres
Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git, GitHub

2003 to 2004 Higher Diploma: Engineering

Dublin Institute of Technology

1996 to 2000 BSc (Hons): Physics

NUI Maynooth

EXPERIENCE

2007 to 2023 Customer Support Engineer

Siemens Healthineers

- Performed onsite installation, modification, maintenance, and repair of Ultrasound, X-Ray, and Dicom (Digital imaging & Communications in Medicine) PACS (Picture Archive and Communication System) systems.
- Dicom PACS systems involved both server and client PC hardware installation.
- PACS system software and SQL database was then installed and configured.
- Provided technical support both onsite and remote to troubleshoot, repair, and maintain operational efficiencies of all mechanical, electrical, and computer-based systems.

- Trained users to operate new software and computer equipment.
- Documented repair and maintenance reports to track history and maintain accurate records.

2006 to 2007 Customer Support Engineer

Tokyo Electron – Leixlip

- Job responsibilities included the installation of new TEL Lithography systems
- Maintaining the Installed base at the customer site, upgrading and modifications to existing equipment
- Responsibilities also included interfacing with the customer and driving system optimization, together with continuous improvement projects to ensure maximum Customer satisfaction.

2005 to 2006 Customer Support Engineer (Contract)

Xsil Ltd - Dublin

- Job responsibilities included the installation of Xsil's upgraded laser micro-machining systems from gas-assist laser cutting to water-assist
- Power up and software upgrade of installed machines, Servicing coherent lasers, Genmark Robot configuration, XY stage configuration, calibration of vision systems
- Qualification and acceptance of machines to be handed back to HP to be used in their high-volume laser cutting manufacturing.

2002 to 2003 Equipment Operator

Pfizer Pharmaceutical - Australia

• Traveled around the world working in Australia on the way.

2000 to 2002 Lithography Engineer

Intel Ireland – Leixlip

INTERESTS

My interests are golf, GAA, and swimming. Spending time with my family and being involved with my three kid's sports clubs.